{
    "id": "63a4014d6ebd423593d1f9b10d3c2720",
    "title": "Gap Filling Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "My grandfather ........................... at",
            "description": "The simple past is used to talk about a finished event.",
            "answers": [
                "dead",
                "has died",
                "died",
                "dies"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctors said that he was ................................ on arrival.",
            "description": "Dead on arrival is the correct expression.",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "dead",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she left home at six, she .............................. be here soon.",
            "description": "We use should to express logical possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "should",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Whenever we meet, we ............................. politics.",
            "description": "Discuss is one of those verbs that does not take a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "discuss",
                "discuss on",
                "discuss about"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Have you ................................ for this drink?",
            "description": "Paid is the past and past participle form of pay. ",
            "answers": [
                "paid",
                "payed",
                "pay"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He .............................. me a visit the other day.",
            "description": "To pay a visit is to visit someone. Paid is the past form of pay.",
            "answers": [
                "payed",
                "paid",
                "make"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It took them hours to ............................ the fire in the basement.",
            "description": "To put out fire is to extinguish it.",
            "answers": [
                "put off",
                "put up",
                "put out"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What a brilliant idea ................................!",
            "description": "In exclamatory sentences, the subject goes before the auxiliary verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is it",
                "it is",
                "does it"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Tell me where .............................. all this while.",
            "description": "In reported questions the inverted word order is used.",
            "answers": [
                "were you",
                "have you been",
                "you have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………… give me my money back.",
            "description": "Had better is used to give strong advice. ",
            "answers": [
                "have better",
                "had better",
                "better"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She worked hard so that she ............................. the promotion.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, would, could or might are common in the clause introduced by so that.",
            "answers": [
                "gets",
                "will get",
                "would get"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "That child of ................................ has broken my window again.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "your",
                "your's",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}